<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<item><pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2015 05:51:10 -0500</pubDate><title><![CDATA[About Our Clinics]]></title><url><![CDATA[about-our-clinics]]></url><meta><![CDATA[]]></meta><metad><![CDATA[]]></metad><menu><![CDATA[About Our Clinics]]></menu><menuOrder><![CDATA[0]]></menuOrder><menuStatus><![CDATA[Y]]></menuStatus><template><![CDATA[template.php]]></template><parent><![CDATA[about-us]]></parent><content><![CDATA[&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-6 col-md-6&quot;&gt;&lt;img id=&quot;bor&quot; src=&quot;data/uploads/About.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-6 col-md-6&quot;&gt;
		&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;Gateway clinic is the &lt;strong&gt;&#039;Center of Excellence&#039;&lt;/strong&gt; for gastroenterology, laparoscopic surgery, Hepatobiliary- pancreatic surgery, colorectal surgery, endoscopy - diagnostic and therapeutic, endoscopic gynaecological surgery and bariatric surgery. Patients are&lt;span id=&quot;cke_bm_38E&quot; style=&quot;display: none;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt; managed by well experienced surgeons, anesthesiologists, gynecologists, gastroenterologists, endocrine specialists, cardiologists, pulmonologists and other supportive medical team and paramedical staffs.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;Patients will be benefited by the vast experienced doctors who are trained in managing all complicated medical and surgical problems. This centre has got the well stocked teaching materials, videos and training facilities for the younger surgeons to get benefited.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-12 col-md-12&quot;&gt;
		&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr. K. Sendhil kumar&lt;/strong&gt; delivers new energy and excellence to his patients by his years of experience in gastro surgery and new techniques and technologies equipped at highly advanced endo and laparoscopy centre &quot; Gateway Clinics &quot;. In keeping with our philosophy a multidisciplinary approach to the investigation and management of gastro intestinal disorders is served by an endoscopy unit that incorporates the use of state of art Endoscopic technology.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;A special attraction is brought by our emphasis on &lt;strong&gt;&quot; DAY CARE SURGERY &quot;&lt;/strong&gt; for pathologies of appendix, Uterus, Ovaries, Gall bladder, Inguinal and abdominal Hernias, Piles, anal fissure and fistula problems. It wins the advantages of less than 24 hrs of hospital stay (early discharge), less pain and blood loss, immediate return to normal activity.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;Installation of various latest equipments like harmonic scalpel, vessel sealing device, High definition cameras, and staplers adds up the reputation of Day care surgery for patients comfort.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;We, at Gateway clinic specialize in the investigation and management of all forms of gastrointestinal diseases to ensure that the provision of care for our patients is of the highest caliber with improved quality of life.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
]]></content><private><![CDATA[]]></private><author><![CDATA[admin]]></author></item>
