<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<item><pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 06:59:31 -0400</pubDate><title><![CDATA[Colonoscopy]]></title><url><![CDATA[colonoscopy]]></url><meta><![CDATA[]]></meta><metad><![CDATA[]]></metad><menu><![CDATA[Colonoscopy]]></menu><menuOrder><![CDATA[10]]></menuOrder><menuStatus><![CDATA[Y]]></menuStatus><template><![CDATA[template.php]]></template><parent><![CDATA[services]]></parent><content><![CDATA[&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-12 col-md-12&quot;&gt;&lt;img id=&quot;bor&quot; src=&quot;data/uploads/innerbanner15.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-12 col-md-12&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
		&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;Colonoscopy is a procedure that lets your doctor look inside your entire large intestine. It uses an instrument called a colonoscope, or scope for short. Scopes have a tiny camera attached to a long, thin tube. The procedure lets your doctor see things such as inflamed tissue, abnormal growths, and ulcers.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-9 col-md-9&quot;&gt;
		&lt;h5&gt;Indications for a colonoscopy:&lt;/h5&gt;
		&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;1. To look for early signs of cancer in the colon and rectum.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;2. To look for causes of unexplained changes in bowel habits.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;3. To evaluate symptoms like abdominal pain, rectal bleeding, and weight loss.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;4. Can also remove polyps from your colon during a colonoscopy (Polypectomy).&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-3 col-md-3&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumbnail&quot; src=&quot;data/uploads/coloscopic-polypectomy.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-12 col-md-12&quot;&gt;
		&lt;h5&gt;What Preparation is Required?&lt;/h5&gt;
		&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;The rectum and colon must be completely emptied of stool for the procedure to be performed. In general, preparation consists of consumption of a special cleansing solution or several days of clear liquids, laxatives and enemas prior to the examination. We will provide you with instructions regarding the cleansing routine necessary for the colonoscopy.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;Follow our instructions carefully. If you do not complete the preparation, it may be unsafe to perform the colonoscopy and the procedure may have to be rescheduled. If you are unable to take the preparation, contact us.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;Most medications can be continued as usual. Medication use such as aspirin, non-steroidal anti-inflammatories, blood thinners and insulin should be discussed with us prior to the examination.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
]]></content><private><![CDATA[]]></private><author><![CDATA[admin]]></author></item>
