<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<item><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 09:22:24 +0200</pubDate><title><![CDATA[Our Products]]></title><url><![CDATA[our-team]]></url><meta><![CDATA[]]></meta><metad><![CDATA[]]></metad><menu><![CDATA[Our Team]]></menu><menuOrder><![CDATA[3]]></menuOrder><menuStatus><![CDATA[Y]]></menuStatus><template><![CDATA[nosidebar.php]]></template><parent><![CDATA[]]></parent><content><![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;We understand that ‘Teamwork’ is the singular most valued asset required for any organization. Our promoters with valued experience in varied sectors of the hospitality industry are ever ready to take up the most challenging tasks and our assurance is that we will exceed your expectations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
		&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;thumbnail center-block&quot; src=&quot;http://localhost/website04/data/uploads/our-team.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 220px; height: 180px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-8&quot;&gt;
		&lt;h4&gt;Ajith Rama Varma, Managing Director&lt;/h4&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;Hospitality professional with more than 18 years’ experience in hotel &amp;amp; restaurant operations &amp;amp; food service consulting, Ajith is instrumental in design and sales functions at I-Kat.&lt;br /&gt;
			His previous experiences are with Taj Group of Hotels, Gerard Café (hospitality) &amp;amp; Angelo Po Grandi Cucine (food service equipment). In his efforts to update with the latest trends, he has widely travelled to visit exhibitions and factories of major suppliers in Europe &amp;amp; Asia.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;h4&gt;Manoj Chalil, Managing Director&lt;/h4&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;Electrical engineer with 20 years’ experience in facilities management, Manoj heads the technical team and oversees the manufacturing, on site engineering and all support processes. Manoj’s expertise in food service equipment maintenance and sourcing of components has been the key to the success of I-Kat.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
]]></content><private><![CDATA[]]></private><author><![CDATA[admin]]></author></item>
